

Bachtiar Ramadhan

Data Enthusiast | FrontEnd Developer



Bandung, Jawa Barat



M bachtiarramadhan26@gmail.com



6285213921331

Hello! I am currently enrolled at the International University of Logistics and Business as a final-year student, specializing in Information Technology. My expertise lies in Front End Development, which I am honing through courses. In addition, I am also currently enhancing my skills in data analysis and AI as part of my self-development journey. During my professional career, I have successfully completed various projects ranging from web applications to decision-maker prediction models. My latest project is an Enterprise Resource Planning application.



Work Experience



IT Staff | Front End Developer • Universitas Logistik dan Bisnis Internasional (ULBI)

April 2023 - March 2024

Some of the applications created:

- ULBI Graduates App
- ULBI Session Registration & Submission App
- ULBI Employee Attendance App
- ULBI Quality Assurance Information System App
- New Student Admission 2023/2024 App
- New Student Admission 2022 App
- Webometrics App
- ULBI Employee Correspondence Application

Research Assistant • Universitas Logistik dan Bisnis Internasional (ULBI)

Januari 2022 - March 2024

- Participate in the 2022 Research Grant at the Poltekpos. The responsibilities held are making Research Reports, Research Posters, Presentation Slides, and Python Program Code.
- Participated in the 2023 Research Grant at the University of Logistics and Business International. The responsibilities held are making Research Reports, and Research Posters.
- Provide data science training at Pre-Morris 2023 and Morris 2023.
- Create training related to GoLang Programming and Vanilla Javascript.

Assistant Lecturer • Universitas Logistik dan Bisnis Internasional (ULBI)

October 2021 - November 2021

- Responsible for providing Machine Learning material in Database I Course at Politekpos
- Responsible for providing Machine Learning material in the BigData Course at STIMLOG.

Machine Learning Graduate • Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, &



Traveloka

August 2023 - Januari 2024

[Bangkit Graduate with Distinction]

- Trained to learn machine learning, starting from the basics of Python programming to using the TensorFlow library developed by Google.
- Create and develop useful projects using multiple technologies consisting of Android, Google Cloud Platform, and TensorFlow Machine Learning.



Trainer Data Science • Intelligo ID

April 2022 - September 2022

• Provide training related to data mining stages using the Python programming language.

Content Creator • Intelligo ID

Oktober 2021 - April 2022

• Create posts related to mini-class events, bootcamps, and informational content about data science.

External Projects

- JPO Enterprise Resource Planning
- Maternal & Child Health System (Intern Project)
- Postal Employee Management System (Intern Project)

Education

Universitas Logistik dan Bisnis Internasional (ULBI)

Informatics • 2020 - 2024

- Project 1: Analysis of E-Commerce Application "Tokopekita" Website Based
- Project 2: Analyzing Employee Data to Predict Salary Based on Specific Factors with Machine Learning Approach
- Project 3: Data-driven Modeling to Predict Salary Based on Specific Factors with Machine Learning Approach
- Internship 1: MentalCare Application to Predict Treatments for Anxiety Disorders and Depression
- Internship 2 : Effect of Hyperparameter Tuning on the Effectiveness of the Hybrid Approach in Stress and Depression Diagnostics A Systematic Literature Review

SMAN 2 Kuningan

Natural Sciences • 2016 - 2019

• Graduation Rate: 86.0

Certificate

• Golang Programming: Beginner to Advanced

- Google IT Automation with Python
- Google Data Analytics
- Mathematics for Machine Learning and Data Science
- Machine Learning
- TensorFlow: Data and Deployment
- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer

Skill

- JavaScript
- PHP (Laravel & Code Igniter)
- GoLang
- Python
- Machine Learning
- Data Analyst
- SQL

Language

- Indonesian
- English

Powered by CakeResume